# HEMAYATULLAH ARIFI

# Machine Learning & Python Developer

⊠ hemayatullaharifi@gmail.com

**(+93)** 771010503

% https://hemayat-arifi.github.io/Portfolio

PD 9, Kabul

#### SUMMARY

As an enthusiastic programmer with 2+ years of experience, I am passionate about exploring machine learning and software development. I have successfully completed a range of projects in data science, deep learning, web applications, and Python programming.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2022 - current

# Python Developer

Remote

#### Uvocorp.com

I bridged the gap between clients and their academic or professional requirements, ensuring timely, high-quality completion of programming and machine learning projects. I maintained open communication to address queries and provide project updates.

2019 - 2021

**Customer Service Sales Representative** 

Kabul, AF

#### MTN Afghanistan

As a front desk customer service agent at MTN Telecommunication, I provided topnotch customer service by addressing inquiries, replacing SIM cards, processing registrations, and resolving technical issues. This experience enriched my customer service, problem-solving, and organizational skills, offering insights into the telecom industry.

2018 - 2019

Sales Executive

Kabul, AF

## Asia Bridge Telecom

As a Sales Executive at Asia Bridge Telecom, I specialized in presenting our services to prospective and new customers, persuading them to choose our ISP solutions. This role enhanced my sales and communication skills, crucial in the competitive telecom industry.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Languages Python, SQL, JavaScript

Libraries/Frameworks TensorFlow, Flask, Keras, Scikit-learn, Django, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib

Tools / Platforms GIT, GitHub, PyCharm, Sublime

Databases PostgreSQL, SQLite, MySQL

#### **EDUCATION**

Pachelors Computer Science

Kabul, AF

Dunya University of Afghanistan

Dunya University of Afghanistan

High School Diploma

Kabul, AF

Azad Khan High School

# **CERTIFICATIONS / COURSES TAKEN**

- TensorFlow Developers Guide Udemy
- Machine Learning & Deep Learning Bootcamp Udemy
- SQL and PostgreSQL (The Complete Developer's Guide) Udemy
- Complete SQL Bootcamp Udemy
- Data Structures & Algorithms Udemy
- Django 4 Master Class Udemy
- Flask Web Developer Bootcamp Udemy
- Python 100 Days of Code Udemy
- HTML & CSS Basics to Advance Codecademy

## **PROJECTS**

#### 1. Family App

A Social media web application built with Python, Flask, and PostgreSQL which is integrated with CDN storage and includes below features:

- User Authentication
- Create & Delete a Post (Text or Photo)
- Comment & Like Post
- Create & Join Family (Groups)
- · Friend Requests & Notifications

#### 2. Face Detection Desktop App

A model based on Convolutional Neural Networks (CNN) can detect a person's face over the picture or video stream. The GUI program is able to represent over 95% accuracy on unseen data.

## 3. English Dictionary App

A web-based dictionary that defines all English words with 10 examples and audio sound for pronunciation using third-party API.

For more of my projects, please refer to the portfolio section at the heading of this resume.